Finding Aid for the Robert Manson Myers Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Robert Manson Myers Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0308
42.92 linear_feet
- From Beowulf to Virginia Woolf
  - Typescript (draft), 1945 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1945 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1947 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1947 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1947 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1947 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1949 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1949 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (two copies), 1950 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), no date (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), no date (Box 1)
  - Typescript (draft), no date (Box 1)
  - Typescript (fragments), no date (Box 1)
  - Typescript (abridged version-two copies), no date (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten draft (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition (photocopy), 19 May 1982 (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition (photocopy), 1 January 1984 (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition (photocopy), 30 March 1984 (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition (photocopy), 30 March 1984 (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition, no date (Box 1)
  - Typescript-Revised Edition, no date (Box 1)
  - Reproduction Proof, 1 July 1984 (Box 1)
  - First Page Proof-Revised Edition (photocopy) (Box 1)
  - Second Page Proof-Revised Edition (photocopy) (Box 1)
  - Page Proof (photocopy), three copies (Box 1)
  - Page Proof (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Requests for Permission to Reproduce/Publish Illustrations (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 1)
  - *Typescript (draft), no date [horribly mildewed] (Box 1)
- Handel, Dryden and Milton; and Restoration Comedy
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Preface, Contents and Appendices (drafts), 1949 (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and MzZton--Handwritten draft (Chapters 1-2) (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton--Handwritten draft (Select Bibliography) (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Appendices A-H; J (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Appendix D (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-List of Illustrations and Index (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Select pages with changes (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Typescript (carbon), no date (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Typescript (carbon), no date (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton--Typescript (carbon), no date (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Page Proof (with notes), no date (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Corrected Proof, 6 September 1955 (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Couected Proof, 3 February 1956 (Box 2)
  - Handel, Dryden and Milton-Final Page Proof, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Notes (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Notes (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript (two copies), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Page Proof (with corrections) (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Page Proof (with corrections) (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Page Proof (with corrections) (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Page Proof (with corrections) (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Draft (handwritten and typewritten, various pages), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy, A Story-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy: A Satire-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy--Typescript (carbon with notations), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript (with corrections), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript (with maps), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy--Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Typescript (with notations), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration ConieJv-Typescript (fragmented; with notations), no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy--Typescript, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Handwritten draft, no date (Box 2)
  - Restoration Comedy-Notes (Box 2)
- The Children of Pride
  - Complete typescript (with corrections) (Box 3)
- The Children of Pride
  - Final Typescript (carbon)- Text through "Who's Who" (Box 4)
- The Children of Pride
  - Final Typescript (carbon)- Index (Box 5)
- The Children of Pride
  - Notes for Index (Box 6)
- The Children of Pride
  - Dead Matter (page proofs) (Box 7)
- The Children of Pride
  - Page Proofs (oversize) (Box 8)
- The Children of Pride
  - Endpaper Maps (oversize/ flat) (Box 9)
- The Children of Pride
  - Page Proof (with corrections), Abridgment Proof (Box 10)
- The Children of Pride
  - Page Dummy (Box 11)
- The Children of Pride
  - Press clippings and reviews (Box 12)
- The Children of Pride
  - Press clippings and reviews (oversize) (Box 13)
- A Georgian at Princeton; Quintet; and Early Articles
  - A Georgian at Princeton--Conected Typescript (Chapter 1), no date (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Corrected Typescript (Chapters 2-3), no date (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Corrected Typescript (Chapters 4-5), no date (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Corrected Typescript (Chapters 6-7), no date (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Conected Typescript (Chapters 8-10), no date (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (Chapters 1-2) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (Chapters 3-6) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (Chapters 7-10) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-PageProof and Notes (Chapters 1-2) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (Chapters 3-6) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (Chapters 7-10) (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-PageProof (oversize) pages 1-119 (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-PageProof (oversize) pages 120-219 (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (oversize) pages 220-299 (Box 14)
  - A Georgian at Princeton-Page Proof (oversize) pages 300-365 (Box 14)
  - Quintet- "The Courtship of Mary Jones, A Play in Two Acts", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- "A Georgian at Princeton, A Play in Two Acts", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- "Voices of Pride, A Play in Two Acts", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- "The Night Season, A Drama for One Player", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Jacket photograph and negative (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (revised) Introduction through "A Georgian at Princeton", 1990 (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (revised) "Voices of Pride" through "The Night Season", 1990 (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (photocopy) Introduction through "A Georgian at Princeton", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (photocopy) "Voices of Pride" through "The Night Season", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (revised) Introduction through "A Georgian at Princeton", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (revised) "Voices of Pride" through "The Night Season", no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript Introduction, 27 March 1989 (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Typescript (revised) Introduction, no date (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Correspondence with Patti P. Gillespie (author of Introduction) (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Revised Typescript (photocopy) Introduction through "A Georgian at Princeton" (Box 14)
  - Quintet- Revised Typescript (photocopy) "Voices of Pride" through "The Night Season" (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Mary and Myself, A Novel" by Anees K. Buckleh, 1950 (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "The Great Dr. Burney: His Life, His Travels, His Works, His Family...", book review by Manson Myers, no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Fifty Sermons on Handel's Messiah", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "The Old Dominion Looks to London", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Neo-Classical Criticism of the Ode for Music", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Anna Seward: An Eighteenth-Century Handelian", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Early Moral Criticism of Handelian Oratorio", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Samuel Butler: Handelian", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "The Old Dominion Looks to London: A Study of English Literary Influences upon The Virginia Gazette (1736-1766)", no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Fifty Sermons on Handel's Messiah", (with corrections), no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Anna Seward: An Eighteenth-Century Handelian", (w/corrections), no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Samuel Butler: Handelian", (with corrections), no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "Mrs. Delany: An Eighteenth-Century Handelian", (with corrections), no date (Box 14)
  - Early Articles- "The Musical Ode in Neo-Classical Criticism", 1943 (Box 14)
- Early essays, class notes and assignments
  - Earlywritings of R. M. Myers, 1929-1939 (Box 15)
  - Poems, short stories and other writings, 1930's-1940 (includes notes and critiques by Donald Davidson) (Box 15)
  - Class notes- History I (Dr. Earl Lee Cruickshank, Prof.), Vanderbilt University, 1937-38 (Box 15)
  - Lecture Topics and Course Outlines- History I and History 410, Vanderbilt University, 1937-39 (Box 15)
  - Class notes- Survey of English Literature and Survey of American Literature (Dr. W. C Curry and Dr. Edwin Mims, Profs.), Vanderbilt University, 1938-39 (Box 15)
  - Essays- written by Manson Myers, 1938-43 (Box 15)
  - Class notes- History 410 (Dr. Earl Lee Cruickshank, Prof), Vanderbilt University, 1939-40 (Box 15)
  - Class notes- Psychology 201 (Dr. Norman L. Nunn, Prof.) Vanderbilt University 1940; Philosophy 201 (Dr. Eugene Bugg, Prof), Vanderbilt University 1939; American History (Dr. W. H. Yarbrough, Prof), Peabody Demonstration School, 1936-37 (Box 15)
  - Class notes- Shakespeare, Chaucer, Spenser, Milton Drama (Dr. Walter Clyde Curry, Prof), Vanderbilt University Spring, 1940 (Box 15)
  - Essays- written by Manson Myers, 1940-41 (Box 15)
  - Essays-History 426 and other courses, Vanderbilt University, 1940-41 (Box 15)
  - Exams and reviews- History 304 (Dr. Walker, Prof), Vanderbilt University, 1940-41 (Box 15)
  - Class notes- The Eighteenth Century and The Nineteenth Century (Marjorie Hope Nicolson, Prof.), ColumbiaUniversity 1941-42; Neo-Classical Criticism (George W. Sherburn, Prof), Harvard University 1943; Sir Gawain and the Green Knight (Frank P. Magoun, Prof), Harvard University (Box 15)
  - Class notes- English 431 (Donald Davidson, Prof), Vanderbilt University, 1941 (Box 15)
  - Paper (Senior Thesis?)- History 404, Vanderbilt University, 1940-41 (Box 15)
- Early essays, class notes and assignments
  - Class notes- The Sixteenth Century (Harry Morgan Ayres, Prof), Columbia University 1941-42; Comprehensive English (Edwin Mims, Prof), Vanderbilt University (Box 16)
  - Class notes-Gothic-Comparative Philology 170 (Whatmough, Prof), Harvard University 1942-43; Icelandic Language and Literature (Frank P. McGoun, Prof.), Harvard University, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Class notes- Comparative Romantic Literature (Emery Neff, Prof), Columbia University, 1943-44 (Box 16)
  - "Blood on the Thorn: A Play in Three Acts", by Manson Myers, New York, 1943-44 (Box 16)
  - Sample Tests- Manson Myers (student and teacher), various courses, 1943-56 (Box 16)
  - Assignments and Lecture Notes- English 100 and English 209R (taught by Manson Myers), 1947 (Box 16)
  - Assignments and Lecture Notes- English 200 (taught by Manson Myers), 1947 (Box 16)
  - Assignments and Lecture Notes- English 325 and 326 (taught by Manson Myers), 1947 (Box 16)
  - Gradebook- for "The American Novel between the Wars (1920-1940)", Newport News High School (taught by Manson Myers), 1947; and, "The Modern Novel", English 385 (taught by Manson Myers), Newcomb College, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Class Assignments- English 202 Great British Writers (taught by Manson Myers), Newcomb College, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Lecture notes, assignment lists, lecture schedules and study questions- various courses (taught by Manson Myers), 1952 (Box 16)
  - Reading lists and examinations- various courses (taught by Manson Myers), 1959-1969 (Box 16)
  - Test questions and reading lists- New Orleans (taught by Manson Myers), no date (Box 16)
  - Test questions, teaching notes and entrance examination to Class IX- The Brearley School (taught by Manson Myers), no date (Box 16)
  - Teaching notes and assignment lists- Yale University (taught by Manson Myers), no date (Box 16)
  - Lists of books, novels and poems, no date (Box 16)
- Travel
  - England, 1953-1955- news clippings, receipts, tourist information, correspondence (Box 17)
  - University College, London (M. Myers was a Fulbright Scholar 1953-54)-correspondence, information about the College, announcements of lectures (Box 17)
  - Handel-Purcell Festival, London (June 1959)- announcements and programs (Box 17)
  - England, 1968- business cards, receipts (for antiques, hotel, travel), correspondence (Box 17)
  - England, 1969- copy of Times (Wed., July 2, 1969-"Investiture of Prince Charles"), receipts, tickets, laundry lists, correspondence (Box 17)
  - Europe, 1970- receipts (purchases of antiques), tickets, theater programs (Box 17)
  - England, 1970- airline ticket, hotel confirmations, addresses, receipts, correspondence, lease agreement (The Chesterfield House) (Box 17)
  - England, January 1973- theater programs, copy of the January 4, 1973 Times (Box 17)
  - England, Summer 1973- business cards, receipts, correspondence (Box 17)
  - London, Summer 1974- receipts (for antiques), correspondence (Box 17)
  - England and Holland, December 1974- January 1975- tickets, receipts, business cards, theater programs, correspondence (Box 17)
  - England December 1976- January 1977- correspondence, brochures, business cards, itinerary (Box 17)
  - Society for Theater Research- correspondence, newsletter, membership and society information (Box 17)
  - National Book League- correspondence, information on the League (Box 17)
- Travel
  - Rotterdam- concert programs, theater programs (Box 18)
  - Various travel brochures, maps, tickets (travel and entertainment), receipts, correspondence, (no dates) (Box 18)
- Appointment Books 1943, 1945-1983
- Appointment Books, 1984-1997
- Books
  - EarlyMoral Criticism of Handelian Oratorio, 1947 (23 copies) (Box 21)
  - Anna Seward: An Eighteenth-CenturyHandelian, 1947 (9 copies) (Box 21)
- Books
  - Restoration Comedy, 1961 (89 copies) (Box 22)
- Books
  - A Georgian at Princeton (Box 23)
- Books
  - A Georgian at Princeton (Box 24)